(谁是老大)
《行尸走肉》
卡森
Carson.
我们刚检查完
We were just finishing up.
快点
Chop-chop.
你好  小德
Hi, D.
达里尔  对吧
Daryl, right?
别跟他说话
Don't talk to him.
是阴性的
It's negative.
也许下次吧
Well, maybe next time.
抱歉
Sorry.
还在习惯做我自己的助手
Still getting used to being my own assistant.
不管他们说什么
Whatever they say...
-照做就行  -我说了别跟他说话
- just do it. - ‭I said don't talk to him.
好  来看看
Okay, let's take a look.
会好转的  如果你配合
It'll get better -- if you let it.
尼根会照顾你
Negan will take care of you.
相信我
Trust me.
小德怀特
Dwighty boy.
我得跟我的朋友聊会儿
I need to talk to my associate for a minute.
去做你的事吧
Go about your business.
除了你
Except for you.
你站在那儿
You, stand right there.
坐下
Sit.
来了
Coming.
来...
C-- Oh!
我渐渐知道怎么用这玩意儿了
You know, I'm getting the hang of this thing.
那就是你的下场  混蛋
That's you, asshole.
除非你放聪明点
Unless you're smart.
你自己选
Your choice.
你可以跟他们一样
You could be like them...
或者跟我一样
...or me.
或者跟它们一样
Or them.
少受点罪吧
Make it easy on yourself.
我不会下跪
I ain't ever gonna kneel.
我也这样说过
Yeah, I said that, too.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
瞧
See...
这就是问题所在
...that's the thing, man.
你不理解
You don't.
但你会的
But you're gonna.
他要疯了
He is going ape-shit!
是啊
Yep.
而你呢  你在火上浇油
And you? You are hustling.
起作用了
It's working.
虽然见效很慢  但是
It's working slow, but, hey, man,
有些人就是更难击溃
some people are harder to break than others.
是啊  他快了
Yeah. He's close.
没错
Yeah, he is.
既然你做得这么好
Since you're doing such an awesome job,
你想跟之前的老熟人
you want to have a little blast from the past
玩一玩吗
with you-know-who?
我开玩笑的  放松点
I'm kidding, man. Lighten up.
你想选谁都行  只要她愿意
Pick whoever you want, as long as she says yes.
糟了
Oh, crap.
你下面还好吗
Are you okay down there?
你的老二
Your penis?
那家伙  他...
I mean, that guy, he, uh...
狠狠咬了一口
clomped on it.
它会不会...
Or is it...
已经萎了
down for the count? ‭
我没事
I'm fine.
但不用了
But I'm gonna pass.
我挺好的
Man, I'm cool.
但你真的"好"吗  德怀特
Are you cool, though, Dwight?
我刚刚可是说了
I mean, I just said
小妞任选  供君消遣
that it was happy hour at the Pussy Bar
德怀特可以免费享用
and Dwight eats for free,
而你却告诉我说"不用了"
and you're telling me no?
这叫"好"吗
Is that cool?
我的工作还没完成
I haven't finished the job.
我还不配得到奖赏
I-I haven't earned it yet.
是吧
Right?
你说什么屁话呢
The hell you talking about?
付出就有收获
You earn what you take.
出现橙色事件
We have an orange situation.
给我
Give me that.
阿拉特  什么情况  有人偷东西吗
Arat, what do you got? Grab-a-go?
对  他只能从三条路逃跑
Yeah, he could've only gone three ways --
蛾子那条 天使那条  或者难走的那条
the moth, the angel, or the hard way.
很好
Good.
我是小德  我在门口和你汇合
It's D. I'll meet you at the gate.
我想拿回我的东西
I mean, I want my shit back,
但那是件苦差事
but that is grunt work.
不如让肥乔去吧
Why don't you have Fat Joey go and do it?
他绝对需要多运动运动
God knows he needs the exercise.
而你
You?
你不用去的  德怀特
You don't have to do it, Dwight.
我很乐意去
I'd like to do it.
乖孩子
Good boy.
趁着还能回去  赶紧回去
Go back while you can.
你知道我就回去了
You know I did.
无论他对你做了什么  都还能更糟
Whatever he's done to you, there's more.
总有更糟的
There's always more.
你逃不掉的
You won't get away.
等你被抓回来了  惩罚会更糟
And when you're back, it'll be worse.
吓尿了吗
Are we pissing our pants yet?
你是谁
Who are you?
尼根
Negan.
你是谁
Who are you?
尼根
Negan.
你们是谁
Who are you?
尼根
Negan.
看到了吗
You see that?
我无处不在
I am everywhere.
你用这次逃跑
And this was your shot to prove to me that
证明了这个简单的事实
that fundamental fact was sinking in,
而你输了
and you failed.
这真是糟透了
Which sucks,
因为你的生活本可以变得好很多
because your life was about to get so much cooler.
我说的对吗
Am I right?
对极了
Damn right.
德怀特给了你一些选择
Now, Dwight gave you some options.
我觉得你没搞明白
I don't think you get it yet.
所以我就细说给你听
So I'm gonna break it down for you.
你有三个选择
You get three choices.
第一  你被插在柱子上
One, you wind up on the spike
作为死人替我工作
and you work for me as a dead man.
第二  你从牢里出来  靠工作赚工分
Two, you get out of your cell, you work for points,
但你会生不如死
but you're gonna wish you were dead.
或者第三  你为我效力
Or three, you work for me,
给自己弄一双新鞋
you get yourself a brand-new pair of shoes,
活得像国王一样
and you live like a king!
这选择似乎很明显嘛
Choice seems pretty obvious.
你应该知道  没有第四种选择了
You should know, there is no door number four.
就这些了
This is it.
这是唯一的办法了
This is the only way.
去他妈的
Screw it.
很难吓到你嘛
You don't scare easy.
我喜欢
I love that.
但是露西尔
But Lucille...
她很生气哦
Well, it kind of pisses her off.
她觉得你这样很不敬
She finds it to be disrespectful.
算你走运
Lucky for you,
她今天不是很口渴
she's not feeling too thirsty today.
但我很口渴
But I am.
所以...
So...
我要去喝一杯了
I'm gonna go get me a drink!
达里尔
Daryl?
有很多事  我真希望我永远都不知道
There's so many things I wish I never found out...
我希望我没有试图...
I wish I didn't try...
之前在森林里时
Back in the woods...
在我失去蒂娜之后
after I lost Tina...
我们拿了你的东西  然后决定回去
when we took your stuff, when we decided to go back...
我跟你说了抱歉
I told you I was sorry.
你当时说  "你会后悔的"
And you said, "You're gonna be."
现在我后悔了
I am.
我受伤了
I'm screwed up.
我的摩托废了
My bike's screwed up,
你必须回去  因为你欠着债
and you're going back because you owe.
现在你欠的债更多了
And now you owe a hell of a lot more.
这值得吗
Was it worth it?
让我走吧
Just let me go.
我做不到
I can't.
为什么
Why?
闭嘴
Shut up.
我们以前关系很好
We used to be friendly.
闭嘴
Shut up.
在他做了那些事之后
After everything he did...
对你  对你的妻子所做的事
to you, to your wife...
别提到她
Don't talk about her.
她不是我妻子
She's not my wife.
不再是了
Not anymore.
看看  你无处可去
Look, there's nowhere to go.
一切都是他的  早晚都是
Everything's his or will be.
我知道
I know.
继续走
Keep walking.
我说继续走
I said keep walking!
不要紧的
It's okay.
什么
What?
你开枪也不要紧的
It's okay if you do it.
我理解
I get it.
该死  我希望你打死我  拜托了
Hell, I want you to. Please.
闭嘴
Shut up.
继续走
Keep walking.
我不能回去
I can't go back.
你得回去
You will.
因为没别的选择
'Cause that's the only way.
这只是他的一面之词
See, that's what he tells us.
他说没别的选择  只能按他说的做
That there's no choice, no way but his way.
一个拿着球棒邪笑的恶棍来了
Thug swoops in with a baseball bat and a smile,
而我们那么恐惧  放弃了一切
and we're all so scared that we gave up everything.
他只是一个人  我们有这么多人
Well, there's only one of him and all of us,
为什么我们要这样活着
so why are we living like this?
因为看看我们现在的情况
Because look where we are!
我们以前一直在输
We were losing.
现在不会了
Now we're not.
你知道吗
You know...
我和玛利亚死里逃生的最初几个月...
after me and Maria survived those first few months...
当我们到了那里
when we got there...
我们以为一切会好的
we thought it would be okay.
我们以为自己知道该怎么和怪物抗争
We thought we knew how to fight the monsters.
起来
Get up.
不要紧的  小德
It's okay, D.
起来
Get up!
那里没有任何值得我留恋的东西了
There's nothing back there for me.
这是我今生最后一次下跪
This is the last time I'm going to kneel.
起来
Get up!
-你懂的  -起来
- You feel. - ‭Get up...
我记得  小德
I remember, D.
不然我就把你认识的所有人都丢进栅栏
...or I'll put every person you ever talked to on the fence.
我会蒙住他们的眼睛
I'll blindfold them,
然后逼他们在短暂又可悲的余生中
and I'll make them eat shit sandwiches
吃大便三明治
for the rest of their short, sorry lives.
我会把你妻子的尸体挖出来喂乌鸦
I'll dig up your dead wife and feed her body to the crows.
懂吗
You feel that?
你懂吗
You feel it?!
好吧  小德
Okay, D.
你赢了
You won.
但你知道  我生无可恋
But you know there's nothing left.
能给我一支吗
Can I have one?
他对你好吗
He good to you?
是的
Yeah.
很好
Good.
你...
Are you...
你开心吗
You happy?
是的
Yeah.
很好
That's good.
我做了正确的事
I did the right thing.
总比死强多了
It's a hell of a lot better than being dead.
是啊
Yeah.
吃吧
Eat.
你害死了你朋友
You got your friend killed.
我害死了蒂娜
I got Tina killed.
别装作你不了解真相
And don't pretend like you don't know the score.
你早该死了
You should be dead.
但是尼根看中了你
But Negan's taken a shine to you.
你很走运
You're lucky.
别忘记这点
Don't forget.
祝你胃口好
Bon appetit.
进
Step in.
天啊
Jesus.
你
You...
看起来糟透了
look awful.
别担心
Don't you worry.
我们会让卡森治好你
We'll have Carson fix you all up.
你渴吗  给
You thirsty? Here.
见鬼  我忘了
Ah, hell, I forgot.
你的嘴
Your mouth is all...
肿得像狒狒的屁股
puffed up like a baboon's ass.
需要吸管吗
Need a straw?
小德  给他根吸管
D, give him a straw.
你怎么待客的
What's wrong with you?
看到那家伙了吗
See that guy?
他负责煽风点火
He hustles.
我喜欢煽风点火
I like hustle.
但是信不信由你
But believe it or not,
我们之前并不和睦
things weren't always cool between us.
小德  他要靠工作赚工分
See, D here -- he worked for points,
他和他性感的妻子  还有她性感的妹妹
him and his super hot wife and her super hot sister.
但是妹妹  她需要药物
But, see, sis -- she needed meds.
那玩意儿很难搜集
And that shit is hard to scavenge,
所以价值更高
so it cost more.
妹妹没赚够工分
Sis fell behind on points,
所以我让她嫁给我
so I asked her to marry me.
说我会照顾她
Told her I would take care of her
无论生老病死  等等
in sickness and in health, blah blah blah,
因为我是个顶天立地的男子汉
because I am a stand-up guy.
她告诉我她会想想
She tells me that she's gonna think about it.
接下来呢
Next thing you know,
就出了橙色事件
I'm dealing with an orange situation.
小德怀特偷走了所有的药
Dwighty boy here stole all the medication
带上了他性感的妻子
and took off with his super hot wife
和我性感的准未婚妻跑了
and my super hot maybe soon-to-be fiancée.
所以我必须派人去追他
So I had to send my guys after him.
因为我不能容忍这种事
Because I can't let something like that stand.
这里是有规矩的
There...are...rules.
追他让我付出了很大代价
Cost me an arm and a leg going after him.
你猜怎么着  小德怀特
And you know what -- Dwighty boy?
他还是跑掉了
He still got away.
但问题是
But here's the thing.
小德  他觉悟了
D -- he saw the light.
他拿出了男子气概  他回来了
He manned up. He came back.
他求我原谅他
He asked for my forgiveness.
我喜欢这点
I like that.
让我眼前一亮
Made me... take notice.
但是露西尔
But Lucille...
你知道她是什么样
Well...you know how she is.
她很守规矩
She is a stickler for the rules.
所以德怀特
So, Dwight...
他求我别杀雪莉
...he begged me not to kill Sherry,
我觉得还挺可爱的
which I thought was kind of cute,
所以我只打算杀他
so I was just gonna kill him.
但是然后雪莉说她会嫁给我
But then Sherry says that she will marry me
如果我让德怀特活命的话
if I let Dwight live,
仔细想想  这提议还挺变态的
which, if you think about it, that's a pretty screwed-up deal,
因为我本来要娶的是她妹妹
'cause I was gonna marry her sister
结果她死了  但是
until she wound up dead, but...
雪莉的确非常性感
Sherry is super hot.
总之  这是个好开始
Anyways, it was a start.
但还不够
But it wasn't enough.
所以德怀特
So Dwight...
受了烙铁之刑
he got the iron.
然后我娶了他性感的妻子
And then I married his super hot wife.
前妻
Ex-wife.
经历了这些事  他依然入伙了
And then after all that, he still got on board.
现在看看他
And now look at him.
我最得力的手下之一
One of my top guys.
我们完全和好了
And we are totally cool.
重点是
The point being,
我认为你也能成为那样的人
I think you can be that guy.
我认为你准备好了
I think you are ready to be that guy.
看看周围
You look around here.
这些
This?
都可以归你
Well... it can all be yours.
你用做的只是
All you got to do is
回答一个简单问题
answer one simple question.
你是谁
Who are you?
说不出话了吗
What, does the cat got your tongue?
被这壮丽的景象惊呆了吗
You're just overwhelmed by the awesomeness of this?
我再问你一次
I'm gonna ask you one more time.
你是谁
Who are you?
达里尔
Daryl.
这是唯一的...
Oh, this is the only...
别说话
Hey. Sst, sst, sst.
没关系  小德
It's cool, D.
他做出了选择
He made his choice.
他做出愚蠢的选择不是我的错
Ain't my problem if he made a dumbass choice.
你要么进那个房间
You're gonna wind up in that room
要么挂在栅栏上
or hanging on the fence!
我理解你为什么那样做了
I get why you did it.
你为什么接受
Why you took it.
你是为别人着想
You were thinking about someone else.
这也是我不能接受的原因
That's why I can't.